Welcome to this what's new in expense
agent travel requests.
And this session is not only about
travel requests, it's also about expense
reports because
they arrive
unexpectedly and this is about a feature
that can make this more predictable.
Why travel requests?
Well, first, why not? Because it's
entirely optional. It's just a feature
you can use or not.
But then it gives a way for employees to
ask for permission to spend money.
And for the company, it gives you an
overview of what expenses we can expect.
And
eventually when we you have an audit for
instance, it also serves as
documentation of who authorized a
certain spend.
So, the process is
pretty straightforward. The
employee creates a travel request, the
manager approves,
the employee spends money, the employee
comes back, creates
expense report,
manager approves, accountant posts.
So, the demo is in the business central
client.
The exact same thing will be available
in the
expense agent web app and in the expense
agent
phone app.
It's just not ready at this point when
we're recording these videos.
So, if we look at a
travel request, it can be as simple as I
will create a new one here
and it will be requested for
me. I'm Linda Townsend.
And I want to
visit HQ
and that will cost me
a ticket of 100. That's basically it.
Now we have created a spend request and
we can send it for processing.
Obviously, spend requests will often be
a bit more involved, so I have created
a more realistic one for
somebody wanting wanting to go to a
Directions conference soon.
And you can see there are more fields
here, but before we get to those,
we'll take a look at the lines because
we can also itemize the lines we are
going to ask for because we want to
explain to the your manager what kind of
expenses we expect.
So there will be some flight and the
flight we usually would buy in our local
currency, so that's just a local
currency amount.
But when we are in Paris, we'll
have expenses in euro and you can see
that these amounts are
translated into our local currency.
We have also a schedule to say when do
we expect this travel to be. You can
also say something about
from where and to where are you
traveling.
And the approval just tells you who
approved
and when this was approved. So,
this is approved as you can see
and we expect to use approximately
4,000.
And
let's now go to
expense reports.
It takes some time to enter all this, so
I did that up front. But first of all,
you can see I have entered a travel
request number number two, which is the
one we just looked at
for the Directions in here conference.
And there's an airline ticket which cost
slightly more than expected. There were
the hotel was
a more what more expensive.
And then, you know, there's ticket and
then some
uh cash
expenses.
So, I can
post this.
This was posted, and do you want to open
the posted expense report? Yes, very
much.
So, this is the posted expense report,
but what we want to look at here is the
entries that are related to the expense
report.
As you can see, we have the expense
ledger entries as as expected, but we
also have the employee ledger entry for
the reimbursement amount, was which was
whatever, 100.5.
But, we also have a link between the GL
entries we created and the spend request
or travel request.
But, that's basically
process. So, just for audit, because
um as I also said before, the third
uh use of this is to
be able to audit, see who authorized
this
travel.
And the question was which account we
used. Maybe this one.
So, you can see here we um these are our
entries, and you can see, oh, who
authorized this?
And then you can go and look at spend
requests.
And you can see,
ah, this was Lisa going to conference,
and it was approved by whoever that was.
Another thing we also have is that some
customers are operating in
a country where the um currency is
volatile, or we have they have a high
inflation, and
these travels or travel requests may
appear, you know, months into the
future.
So, what you would do then is
let's say that uh Lisa is going to
Switzerland, which has a pretty stable
and even rising exchange rate, and she
is going to visit a
customer.
What you do then is to say, "Okay,
we know that Swiss francs are expensive,
and our own currency may be declining.
So, therefore, you can say, "Okay, I
want to make the
budgeting in
in Swiss franc."
And then there's an action we can where
we can update the local currency amount
to, you know, fit whatever 10,000 Swiss
francs correspond to when we get there
in a year.
So, that was the demo, and just as short
summarization, so travel request is
something you do before you go, and it
specify how much you want to spend, when
the expense is, why you're going,
what
Let me ask my session.
Where were you going?
Who was going? And that's not just you,
but we also have a list of travelers if
you want to include other people.
Then the expense report is when you are
back, and then you can specify the
travel request over here. And note that
when you do the travel request in the
expense agent, then the
expense report will be created
automatically.
That's important to note. It's only in
the BC that you need to create it
manually. And you can budget in foreign
currency, as I just explained. That's
it. Thank you for watching this video.